问个问题 我需要雇一个助理
Question. I need to hire an assistant.
你觉得雇第二符合资格的
Do you think it would be unethical
是不是违反职业道德啊
to hire the second most qualified candidate?
最符合资格的有什么问题吗
What's wrong with the most qualified?
从斯坦福大学工程系毕业后
And after graduating Stanford engineering,
我拿到了著名的罗德奖学金
I was offered a Rhodes Scholarship.
你有什么问题要问我吗
Do you have any questions for me?
我一定要忍住在他面前痴笑才行
I definitely have to carve out some extra time for giggling.
你不能歧视那个可怜的家伙
You can't discriminate against the poor guy
长得性感帅气就活该被歧视吗
just because he's a smoke show.
我这一辈子都在跟"性感羞辱"作斗争
I've been battling hot-shaming my entire life.
求你别说"帅哥美女的命也很重要"
Please don't say "hot lives matter."
外公 怎么了
Grandpa. What's up?
把这东西还给你妈
Returning this to your mom.
这个帅小伙是谁
Who's the beefcake?
我需要雇个助理
I need to hire an assistant,
这位先生目前是排在第一位的
and this gentleman is currently the frontrunner.
他是像普通人一样领工资
Does he get a normal paycheck,
还是你要把现金塞进他的丁字裤里 像脱衣舞男那样
or are you just gonna stuff ones down his G-string?
我的确惧怕大众戴有色眼镜来看待这事
I do have some trepidation about the optics.
你是应该惧怕 现在是敏感时期
Well, you should. These are sensitive times.
先入为主的认知可能决定了一切
Perception is everything.
我才不在意这些乱七八糟的
I didn't care about any of that crap.
我没有足够的工作量分配给我的助理玛格丽特
I don't have enough work for my assistant, Margaret.
她都跟了我40年了
Been with me 40 years.
我总不能直接把她丢弃
I can't just put her out to pasture
就像处理年迈孱弱的老马一样
like some worn-out plow horse.
那个小老太太该得到一点尊重
The old broad deserves a little respect.
无意冒犯 外公 但我需要的是一个
No offense, Grandpa, but I need someone
能冲锋陷阵的千里马
who can hit the ground running.
玛格丽特更像是撞到人
Margaret's more someone who would hit a pedestrian
都意识不到的糊涂马
and not even realize it.
就算她不是女强人克丽斯蒂·布林克利
Just because she's no Christie Brinkley,
顺便说下 她还比玛格丽特大一岁呢
who, by the way, is a year older than Margaret,
并不意味着我们就该把她丢到垃圾堆里
doesn't mean we throw her on the scrap heap.
那她必须明天就上班
Well, she'd have to start tomorrow.
她能接受周六工作吗
Is she okay working on a Saturday?
这就是雇佣一个
That's the advantage of hiring somebody
早上6点就精力充沛的人的好处
with a few miles on her by 6:00 A.M.,
她那个时间点已经吃了两个水煮蛋
she will have had two soft-boiled eggs
元气十足地准备大干一场了
and be raring to go.
小卡 快点 我们走吧
Cam, come on, let's go.
不行 稍等一会儿 我得弄完这个
No, hold on just a second. I need to finish this.
求你告诉我你不是又在搞写信请愿的事
Please tell me this isn't another letter-writing campaign.
他们不会将我们的街道重新命名的
They're not going to rename our street.
如果改成"玫琳凯大街"
Okay, Mary Kay Place would be
那将是对美国国宝很有趣的致敬
a very fun tribute to an American treasure,
但可惜不是 这次不是为了那个事
but, no, that's not what this is.
小卡 快点 我想快点走
Cam, come on. I want to go.
商店半小时后就开门了
The store opens in a half-hour, okay?
你知道我总是趁这促销买够一年穿的裤子
You know I get all my pants for the entire year at this sale,
32英寸是大众尺码 很多人抢
and 32 is a very, very common pant size.
你要是有哪一天
It'd be great if we could go a day
不提你32英寸的腰围就好了
without you mentioning your 32-inch waist size.
不行 这事很紧急
No, this is urgent.
卡普兰先生砍掉了我在教职工演出会上的
Senor Kaplan cut my "Wind Beneath My Wings" number
《翅膀下的风》独唱曲目 说是时长问题
at the faculty follies "for time."
所以我要向国税局举报他
So I'm turning him in to the IRS
早餐吃的墨西哥卷饼都算作可扣除税款
for deducting his breakfast burritos.
你把生命都浪费在对付这些死对头上了
You're wasting your life with these rivalries.
我有个同事 每次都吃掉我的花生酱
There is a guy at work who always eats my peanut butter,
但我每次都算了 因为人生苦短
but I just let it go because life's too short
他个头也很短 或许那些花生酱
and so is he, and maybe the peanut butter
就是他缺爱的人生里那人间真情的替代品
is just his creamy substitute for human affection.
好了吗 能走了吗 快走吧
Okay? Can we go? Could we please go?
-可以了 -真是谢谢你了
- Yes. - Thank you.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
我... 请问有什么事吗
I'm s-- Uh... C-Can we help you?
我叫莫里·克拉格
Name's Murray Clark.
我是在这房子里长大的
I grew up in this house.
你好 我叫卡梅隆 这是我丈夫米奇尔
Hi. Well, my name is Cameron. This is my husband, Mitchell.
那可真够搞笑的
Well, that's funny.
好吧 我们要出门了
Okay. Uh, so, we were just about to leave.
我所有的裤子都得在...
See, I get all my pants --
我去参战后 就没见过这房子了
I haven't seen this house since I went off to war.
你是想进来
Oh, and you'd like to come in
看一眼曾经居住的房子吗
and take a look around a little bit?
不 不是那样的
No, nothing like that.
我是来死的
I just came here to die.
-什么 -你说什么
- Uh, excuse me? - I'm sorry?
没什么好悲伤的 我死得很快的
Oh, it's nothing sad. I'll just be a minute.
话说 能先给我一杯果汁喝吗
Actually, could I get a juice first?
当然可以
Oh, of course.
-有何不可呢 -好的
- Why not? - Sure, yeah.
-你在干什么 -当一个热情好客的主人啊
- What are you doing? - Being a gracious host.
招待一个想死在这里的陌生人吗
To a stranger who wants to die here?
拜托 米奇尔 不会发生任何事的
Oh, come on, Mitchell, nothing's going to happen.
他这样只是在哭求帮助而已
It's just a cry for help.
那行 如果我买不到一条修身版的法国蓝斜纹棉布裤
Okay, if I can't get a pair of slim-cut chinos in French Blue,
会死在这里的人将是你
you're gonna die here.
-马文 米尔顿 -不 他叫莫里
- Marvin? Milton? - No, it's Murray.
莫里 莫里 莫里
Murray? Murray! Murray!
天啊 他是真死了吗
Oh, my God. Did he actually die?
冷静 我是获得认证的急救员
Calm down! I'm -- I'm first aid certified!
莫里
Murray?
Murray!!
你的急救知识是谁叫的 死囚病房的保姆吗
Who taught you first aid, a nanny on death row?
-快醒醒 -该死的
- Wake up! - Damn it!
我乘坐经济舱大老远从佛罗里达州飞来
I flew coach all the way from Florida
就为了死在这房子里 结果被你们毁了
to die in this house, and you ruined it!
天啊 真是太疯狂了
Oh, my God. That's insane.
你都知道你要死了 还坐经济舱
You knew you were going to die and you flew coach?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在把简历修改得漂亮点
Oh, I'm trying to spruce up my resume.
找工作简直快要烦死我了
This job hunt is killing me.
我很遗憾 妈
I'm sorry, Mom,
但如果那些公司都不够明智 不肯雇你
but if those companies aren't smart enough to hire you,
那你也不会想跟他们共事的
you don't want to work with them anyway.
以前艾丽克斯找不到男人 我就是这么劝她的
That's what I used to tell Alex about boys.
别拿到第一个邀约就答应
Just don't jump at the first offer.
以前我也是这么叮嘱你不要轻易上男人的钩的
That's what I used to tell you about boys.
他来了 他来了
He's here! He's here!!
今天 我们曾经的邻居 如今的科技大亨
Today, our old neighbor- turned-tech-titan,
肯尼斯 要造访我们家
Kenneth, is coming to visit.
他说他为我准备了一个大惊喜
And he says he has a "big surprise" for me.
我不知道富豪是不是有时间旅行的门路
I don't know if the super rich have access to time travel,
但如果他们有的话 我要回90年代
but if they do, I'm going back to the '90s.
去买一堆亚马逊的股票吗
Ooh, to buy a whole bunch of Amazon stock?
不是
No!
我会叫费莉希蒂不要剪头发
I'm going to tell Felicity not to cut her hair.
太好了
Okay.
-海莉 快来群抱 -不 我就免了吧
- Haley, get in here! - Nah, I'm good.
你不加入 我们是不会放开彼此的
We're not letting go of each other until you get in here.
海莉 快来群抱
Haley, get in the hug!
这感觉太爽了
Oh, this feels so good!
当然了 但是比拥抱更爽的是...
Sure, but who needs hugs when you can...
-男人式握手 -男人式握手
- Man-shake! - Man-shake!
你最好给他们点空间完成这个仪式
You're gonna want to give them some space for this.
搞摄像机来是要干什么啊
Ooh, what are the cameras for?
这是为一部纪录片准备的 要拍科技远见家
This is for a documentary about tech visionaries
回去感谢那些赋予他们灵感的人
going back to thank the people who inspired them.
伊隆·马斯克给他的数学老师买了一座岛
Elon Musk got his math teacher an island.
那我能得到什么
What am I getting?
假设那个人 是我
Assuming it's...me.
-摄像机在拍了吗 -是的
- Well, are the cameras rolling? - Yes.
我们曾经一直梦想一起做的事是什么
What is the one thing that we've always dreamed of doing together?
去纽约跟费莉希蒂一起上大学
Going to college in New York with Felicity?
不是
No.
这个家伙
This man right here,
教我要永远心怀远大的梦想
he taught me to always dream big
伸手摘星辰
and reach for the stars.
为了感谢你 菲尔
And as a thank-you, Phil,
你是否愿意让我成为地球上最幸福的男人
would you make me the happiest man on Earth
和我一起飞离地球
and leave Earth with me?
什么
W-W-What?!
我刚刚订了两张下一趟俄罗斯航班的票
I just got us two tickets on the next Russian flight
飞去国际空间站
to the International Space Station!
这是我遇到过的最意义非凡的事
This is the most amazing thing that's ever happened to me!
除了 当然
Except of -- of course,
非连续两次赢得年度最佳房地产经纪人奖
...winning two non-consecutive Realtor of the Year Awards.
我要哭了
I'm-I'm going to cry.
先别哭 抱歉 刚才收音出了问题
Uh, don't cry yet. I'm so sorry. We had a sound issue.
我们能全重拍一次吗
Can we do all that again?
好的 要从拥抱开始重拍吗
Yeah! Should we take it back to the hug?
我今天演出的票开始预定了
So, tickets for my show today are at will call.
好消息 我给你们预备了免费票
And good news -- I was able to get you comps.
我肯定会以其他方式付出代价
I'm sure it'll cost me in other ways.
是老爸发来的 "我马上就到"
It's from Dad. "I'm almost there."
假如"马上"是个地名 哈维尔肯定是市长
If "almost there" was a place, Javier would be the mayor.
请不要再无来由对他辱骂了
Please stop taking pot shots at his expense.
他这家伙 除了拿来骂也没别的作用了
Pot shots are the only thing that we can take at his expense.
我是认真的 妈 乔都被你的行为毒害了
I mean it, Mom. You've even poisoned Joe.
是被她的烹饪水平毒害了吧
You mean with her cooking?
我们只能嘲笑哈维尔
Hey, we're only making fun of Javier!
不行
No, we're not.
-向我保证 -好吧 我保证
- Promise me. - Okay, fine, I promise.
假如我毫无恶意的玩笑让你不舒服
If my good-natured ribbing is making you uncomfortable,
我会悬崖勒马的
I will refrain.
我给她买了每日一成语
I've got her on Word a Day cards.
我们看看能坚持多久
We'll see how long it holds.
歌洛莉亚
Hola, Gloria.
哈维尔
Oh, Javier, hi--
假牙不错
Nice teeth.
在牙医诊所装的还是钢琴店装的
Did you get them at the dentist or at the piano store?
自打上次摩门教徒上门传教后
I haven't seen anything so white and square
我还没见过如此又白又死性的东西
since the Mormons knocked on my door.
这些还只是我信手拈来的吐槽
And those were just off the top of my head,
但我向曼尼保证了 所以忍了
but I promised Manny, so -- Pbht!
见到你真高兴 快请进
Nice to see you. Come in.
-爸 -乖儿子
- Hey, Dad! - There's my boy!
某人用了我定制的古龙香水
Someone has been wearing my custom-made cologne --
哈维尔之香
Javier!
给想闻起来有点女人味的男人
For the man who wants to smell a little bit like a woman.
多谢你来看我的演出 爸
Thanks for coming to my show, Dad.
当然 我怎么会错过
Of course. I wouldn't miss it.
不过 我进城来还有其他理由
But, hey, that is not the only reason I am in town.
我有个提议
I, um... I have a proposition --
你好好咀嚼一下
something for you to chew on.
你不能替我们咀嚼吗
Couldn't you chew on it for us
毕竟你刚装了一口海狸一样的大牙
with your giant, new beaver mouth?
我为什么要做出那种傻承诺
I don't know why I made that stupid promise.
金句源源不绝
I am on fire!
我在高赌注牌局里拿到了同花顺
I was in a high-stakes poker game with a King-high Flush.
于是我押上了房子
So I bet my house.
不不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
你不能睡在曼尼的房间
You're not living in Manny's room.
我赢下了为期一年的环球航行
I won a year-long cruise around the world.
我希望你能伴我完成整个旅程
I want you to set sail with me for the entire voyage!
-什么 -绝对不行
- What?! - Absolutely not.
我该让百货公司的闺蜜
I should ask my gal at Nordstrom
为我准备几身航海行头
to pull some cruise looks for me.
看看他 急得牙痒痒
Look at him, he's chomping at the bit.
再这样金句要憋不住了
Stop setting me up!
给 老式咖啡
Here you go. A cup of joe, the old-fashioned way.
谢了 玛格丽特
Oh, thanks, Margaret.
老天 这里加了波本酒吗
Oh, God. I-Is there bourbon in this?
你跟我要咖啡的时候
When you asked for coffee,
不是给了我眼神示意吗
didn't you give me a "wink-wink"?
没有 这可是大早上
No. It's the morning.
所以酒里才加了咖啡
Well, that's why there's coffee in it.
请你帮我订个午餐好吗
Could you just make me a lunch reservation, please?
没问题
No problem.
那是什么
What's that thing?
这些餐厅都很棒 杰以前总去
Oh, these are all the great restaurants that Jay used to go to.
你喜欢黛安汁牛排吗
Do you like Steak Diane?
她选了十二家才选到有沙拉的餐厅
It took her 12 tries to find a place that had a salad.
你在做什么
Uh, w-what are you doing?
我刚把沙发铺好
Oh, I was just getting the couch ready
给你午后"开会"时用
for your afternoon "meeting."
你为什么说得好像我不是真要开会
Why are you saying "meeting" like it's not really a meeting?
跟你解释一下
Just so you know,
我的话都是字面意思 没有隐藏含义
when I say something, that's exactly what I mean.
另外 你在车上给我打电话时
Also, when you called me from your car,
我听不清你说什么
I couldn't really understand you.
你或许该重新弄一下蓝牙
You may want to fix your Bluetooth.
你注意到了
You noticed?
几年前牙神经死掉了
The nerve died a few years ago.
假如你看着碍眼 我可以拔掉
But if it bothers you, I'll have it yanked.
曼尼 你的戏讲的是什么
So, Manny, what is your show about?
戏里有海盗和唯美的裸戏吗
Will there be pirates and tasteful nudity?
跟我的上部戏不一样
It'll be different from my last one.
这次是独角戏
This is a one-man play
我会扮演咖啡馆里的四个角色
in which I portray four characters in a café
他们来自各行各业
from different walks of life.
当没有网络信号时
When the Internet goes out,
他们被迫和彼此聊天
they're forced to talk to each other.
我给戏取名为
I call it
《谁什么何时哪里为何无线网》
"Who, What, When, Where, Wi-Fi."
要是我就加个海盗
I'd throw in a pirate.
我该去进入角色了
I should go get into characters.
不准带曼尼去航行
Manny's not going on that trip.
我知道你说的冒险是什么意思
I know what an adventure with you means.
破酒吧 骗徒
Seedy bars, con men,
还有那种赠品笔 一转笔
souvenir pens that when you flip them,
上面的女人就会变成裸体
the lady's clothes come off.
假如我儿子想跟我共度时光
If my son wants to spend some time with me,
他应该有这个自由
he should be able to.
杰 帮我说两句
Jay...back me up.
他不会帮你说话的
He's not gonna back you up.
歌洛莉亚 让曼尼去航行吧
Gloria, let Manny go on the trip.
他不会有事的 他十岁起就像四十岁一样
He'll be fine. He's been 40 since he was 10.
而他四十年来都像十岁一样
And he's been 10 for 40 years.
没门
It's not happening.
我明白你担心什么
Look, I understand your concern,
但我想趁我还有时间 跟曼尼增进感情
but I want to bond with Manny before it's too late.
我可能进入了中年危机
I think I'm having a mid-life crisis.
你或许没注意到 但我做了牙贴面
You probably didn't notice, but I got veneers.
我还在纳闷你哪里不一样了
Oh, that's what that is!
拜托不要死在我们房子里
Please don't die in our house.
你们有什么可在乎的
What the hell do you care?
首先 假如我们以后想卖房子
For starters, if we ever want to sell this place,
我们必须披露这里死过人
we'll have to disclose that someone died here.
为什么 上任房主就没披露
Why? The last owners didn't.
我说了一百万次了 没闹鬼 椅子是我挪的
For the millionth time, I moved that chair.
我妻子几年前去世了 我无亲无故
My wife passed years ago. I don't have any other family.
我只想闭上眼睛 缓缓离开人世
I just want to close my eyes and drift off.
有很多理由让你继续活下去
There are lots of reasons to want to continue to live.
我知道你想念妻子了
I know you miss your missus,
但独自生活比想象得好多了
but living alone is underrated.
例如 你晚饭想吃什么就可以吃什么
For one, you can have whatever you want for dinner.
第二 你想把沙发挪到哪都行
Two, you can move the couch wherever you'd like.
已经十年了
It's been 10 years.
你说沙发挪到哪能更好看
Where-where would the couch look better?
我很感谢你们这不怎么样的鼓励
I appreciate what you think passes for support.
我只是没有兴趣了
I'm just not interested.
我认为你需要更积极的人生观
I think you need a more positive outlook on life.
我们邻居赫歇尔和你年纪差不多
Our neighbor Herschel, he's about your age.
-赫歇尔·布雷弗曼 -是的
- Herschel Braverman? - Yeah.
-我们一起长大的 -我们很喜欢赫歇尔
- We grew up together. - We love Herschel!
我们每次去熟食店
We-we bring him a corned beef sandwich
都给他买咸牛肉三明治
every time we go to the deli.
是的 你看 这就是活下去的理由
Yeah, see? There's something to live for.
-是啊 -你该去和朋友重聚
- Yeah. - You should go reunite with your old friend.
-现在就去 -不如这样
- Right now. - Okay, you know what?
别这么无礼 我们陪他去
Don't be rude. We'll walk him over.
他只是想赶去裤子大特卖
He's just in a hurry to get to a pants sale
特卖已经开始三十分钟了
that started 30 minutes ago.
你是啥 32吗
What are you, a 32?
是的
I am.
32岁 美好年华已经随风散去
All the good stuff's already gone.
如果你们想跟上俄罗斯人的节奏
If you guys want to keep up with the Russians,
就必须练练
you're gonna have to train.
我去拿伏特加
I'll get the vodka!
如果我能造一个仿真女机器人
If I could build a fembot with lifelike skin,
就要造得跟她一样
it would be just like her.
你觉不觉得克莱尔怪怪的
Did you get a weird vibe from Claire?
没啊 她的态度很积极很支持你
No, she seemed super positive and supportive.
就是这样才不正常
That's exactly what I mean.
趁我在厨房 顺便看看有没有果珍饮料
Oh, while I'm here, I'm gonna see if we have any Tang!
我不想去太空 克莱尔 我好害怕
I don't want to go to space, Claire! I'm terrified!
如果我把东西弄坏导致我们不能呼吸怎么办
What happens if I break something and we can't breathe?
天啊 天啊 我现在喘不过气了
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. I can't breathe right now.
亲爱的 冷静 俄罗斯人很懂行啦
Honey, calm down! The Russians know what they're doing!
我会死在那儿的
I'm going to die up there!
告诉他你不想去就好了
Just tell him you don't want to go.
这个礼物太棒了 他一定会受打击的
This is such an amazing gift, it'll crush him.
而且我会在那部纪录片里像个懦夫
Plus, I'll look like a coward in that documentary.
你说得对 我们在片子里不能是那种形象
You're right, we don't want to see this on film.
我脑海中已经想把这难看的片子覆盖了
I'm taping over it already in my mind.
-你必须阻止这件事 -什么
- You've gotta shut this down. - What?!
帮帮我克莱尔 你是我唯一的希望
Help me, Claire. You're my only hope.
好吧
Fine.
但如果我帮了你
But if I do this,
你就不许再跟我引用《星球大战》里的台词
you're not allowed to quote "Star Wars" to me anymore.
-我爱你 -我知道[星球大战台词]
- I love you. - I know.
肯尼思
Hey...Kenneth.
我刚才在那儿和巴兹[扫兴]·奥尔德林聊过了
I was just talking to Buzz-kill Aldrin over here --
克莱尔 我希望你不要介意
Claire, I-I hope you don't mind terribly,
但我刚才瞄了一下你的简历
but I was just taking a peek at your resume.
非常厉害
It is very impressive.
你工作已经有着落了吗
Have you landed anywhere?
目前还没有
Uh, not yet, no.
-说到着落[降落] 很可惜 -真的吗
- You know, speaking of landings, unfortunately -- - Wow, really?
我们应该谈谈一个很有趣的工作机会
Well, we should talk about a really interesting job opportunity
正好我们公司有个空缺
that just opened up at my company.
那太好了
I would love that.
我一直在找一个敢于抓住机会的候选人
I'm looking for a bold candidate who loves to take chances.
不 你正看着的
No, you are looking at a bold candidate
就是一个敢于抓住机会的候选人
who loves to take chances.
我知道 但克莱尔还是
I know, but, still, um, Claire has --
克莱尔有一些担忧
Claire has some concerns.
如果我为你工作 我还能跟你拥抱吗
If I'm working for you, do I still get hugs?
不能 这个季节不能
No, not in this climate. Oh.
我只能跟你来个女人式握手
Best I can offer is a wo-man shake!
什么
Ha! What?
Whoa! What?
-你学得真快 -我是怎么做到的
- Wow, you are a quick study. - How am I doing this?!
记住 把它放进碎纸机 不是传真机
Remember, shred this, don't fax it.
嗨 亲爱的
Hey, honey.
-嗨 杰 -外公
- Hi, Jay. - Grandpa.
给我倒杯咖啡 玛格丽特
Cup of coffee, Margaret?
外公 你来这有事吗
Grandpa, what are you doing here?
今天在曼尼的独角戏上发生了一件惨不忍睹的事
A terrible thing happened today at Manny's one-man show --
他给了我一张票
he got me a ticket.
没事 我就是路过看看玛格丽特做得有多好
No, I just stopped in to see how Margaret's working out.
根本不好
She's not.
虽然我很享受她用夏布利酒
As much as I enjoyed her pairing the glass of Chablis
配给我准备的惊喜鸡尾酒虾
with my surprise shrimp cocktail,
但这不是我需要的助理技能
that's not a skill I need in an assistant.
你必须把她炒了
You have to fire her.
不行 她为我工作了一辈子
I can't. She worked for me her whole life.
她曾睡在人行道上给我买南茜·辛纳特拉的票
She slept on the sidewalk to get me Nancy Sinatra tickets.
好吧 我来说
Fine. I'll do it.
玛格丽特 能请你过来一下吗
Margaret, could you come in here, please?
这是我今天不忍看到的第二件事
This is the second thing today I can't watch.
能做的我都做了
I did everything I could for you.
她是个冷血的人
She's a cold one.
怎么了
What's going on here?
我被开除了吗
Am I fired?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
感谢老天
Oh, thank God!
我已经想退休好几年了
I've been wanting to retire for years now,
但我不想让杰失望
but I could never let Jay down.
我只想睡觉 照顾我的大麻花园
I just want to sleep, tend my cannabis garden,
从此再也不工作
and never work again.
玛格丽特 我想让你来我狗床生意做事
Margaret, I want you back at Dog Beds.
你说了算 杰
Oh, whatever you say, Jay.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
不行
No!
外公 玛格丽特想退休了
Grandpa, Margaret wants to retire.
我想要什么不重要 杰的需要才重要
It's not what I want. It's what Jay needs.
你们两个是怎么回事
Ugh, what is wrong with you two?
你不需要助理
You don't need an assistant,
她也不想再工作了
and she doesn't want to work anymore.
是真的吗 你真的不想干了吗
Is this true? Do you really want to hang it up?
我的确想做点别的事情
There are some things I wouldn't mind trying.
那你应该去做啊 我自己能行
Well, then you should do it. I'll manage.
不过的确是会感觉有点奇怪
It's going to be weird, though.
毕竟你是我此生携手最久的人
I mean, you're the longest relationship I've ever had.
经历过四任丈夫 三次心脏病发作
Four husbands, three heart attacks,
数不清的情人
countless lovers,
你却一直在我身边陪伴我
and you stood by me through it all.
我爱你 杰
I love you, Jay.
我也爱你 玛格丽特
I love you, too, Margaret.
这一路很精彩
It's been a great run.
而且我们还有米奇尔呢
And we'll always have Mitchell.
什么
What?!
她在闹你呢
She's messing with you.
不是啦 我和她的孩子在很久以前就搬走了
No, our kid moved away a long time ago.
把之前我说的话忘了吧
Hey, forget what I told you earlier.
雇好看的那个也没问题
It's okay to hire the hot one.
你可能会交到一辈子的朋友
You may make a friend for life.
你们好啊
Hey, fellas!
你好 赫歇尔
Hey, Herschel!
你们给我带三明治了吗
You bring me a sandwich?
没有 我们今天没去熟食店
Oh, no, we didn't go to the deli today.
别 别 别 等一下
Eh... No, no, no! Wait, wait, wait!
但我们来个回忆之旅怎么样
But how about a trip down memory lane instead?
等等 等等 等等
W-Wait, wait, wait.
赫歇尔 看看 我们找来了你的老朋友
Herschel, look, we have your old friend
-莫里·克拉克 -克拉克
- Murray Clark! - Clark!
还真是世事无常
Well, what do you know?
你好 赫歇尔
Hello, Hersch.
好久不见了
It's been a lifetime.
少给我来这套 你这个目中无人的狗杂种
Don't give me that, you smug son of a bitch.
怎么回事
What -- W-What's happening?
这个混蛋曾跟我们的橄榄球队教练说我是共党
This bastard told our football coach I was a communist.
害我被踢出球队
Got me kicked off the team.
我没准能成职业选手的
I could've gone pro!
我这么做是因为他抢了我送报员的工作
I only did that 'cause he stole my paper route!
害得我只能靠送冰养家糊口
I had to deliver ice to support my family.
送冰 你们到底多大了
Deliver ice? How old are you guys?
-你个奸诈小人 -你卑鄙告密
- You're a snake! - You're a rat!
他趁我去打仗抢了我的女朋友
He stole my girl when I went to war,
还假装瘸腿躲在家里
and he stayed home with a fake limp.
你应该感谢我
You should be grateful!
那个女人传染给我淋病
That woman gave me the clap.
那算是我送你的礼物
That was a little gift from me!
莫里 刚才是怎么回事
Murray, what the heck was that?
这只是个开始
Just the beginning.
什么 什么开始
The beg-- the beginning?
莫里 你在干什么呢 朋友
Oh -- Murray. Uh, what are you doing, buddy?
谁都不许那么跟我说话
Nobody talks to me like that.
好吧
Fine.
我要把它拿走
I'm taking it.
等我回家
And when I get home,
我要帮他报名一大堆邪教
I'm going to sign him up for a bunch of those fringe religions.
看看他喜不喜欢那些唱圣歌的来访者
Let's see how he likes getting all those singing visitors
还有那些免费圣经
and all those free Bibles.
我要把他的余生都毁了
I'm going to ruin the rest of his life.
看啊 米奇尔 他开始为未来做打算了
See, Mitchell, he's making plans for the future.
这就是要有竞争对手的原因 给你活着的动力
That's why you have rivals. It's something to live for.
好了 你只是在给错误的行为找借口
Okay, you're just justifying bad behavior.
莫里 米奇尔上班的地方有个人
Okay, Murray, Mitchell has somebody at work
老是偷吃他的花生酱
that keeps stealing his peanut butter,
他又不愿意做出任何行动
and he won't do anything about it.
你想要制止他吗 往里面加点泻药
You want to stop it? Try mixing in some laxatives.
然后在厕所门挂一个"施工中"的标牌
And then put an "under construction" sign on the bathroom door.
如果你真的想毁了他的一天...
And if you really want to ruin his day --
等等别急 我把这些写下来
Okay, now, hold on, hold on. Let me write these down.
好 就是你打给他老婆
Alright. You call his wife...
无线网断了
Hey, the Wi-Fi's out.
太衰啦 兄弟
Huge bummer, man.
我本来都快写完我的诗啦
I was just about to finish writing my poem.
你也是写作家吗 真是无巧不成书啊
You're a writer, too? Well, knock me over with a feather.
在下布莱恩·勒马克 剧作家
Blaine Lemarque, playwright.
以前河口那边总停电
Power used to go out all the time in the bayou.
真的假的 我正在写一部电影
So crazy, I'm writing a movie set
场景就设在河口 名叫"沼泽警察故事"
in the bayou called "Swamp Cops."
我虽然还在电影学院 但我很快就会家喻户晓
I'm in film school, but soon, everyone's gonna know my name --
基思·范克
Keith Fank!
我不小心听到你们对话
I couldn't help overhearing.
我叫朗达·詹莫威茨 本地的报纸八卦作家
I'm Rhonda Jamowitz, gossip columnist for the local rag.
你们绝对猜不到昨晚是哪颗"星星"降落此处
You'll never guess which starlet was in here yesterday
还带着新男人与更新版的新鼻子
with a new man and a newer nose.
我还一直期待剧会渐入佳境
I was hoping that the play was gonna get better.
以及不会那么多朗达的戏份
With maybe a little less Rhonda.
我知道自己喋喋不休
I know I'm going on and on,
但这是在我母亲过世后
but for the first time since Mother passed,
我第一次不再感到孤单
I don't feel alone.
太棒了
Brilliant.
哪怕没有裸戏也完全没问题
I don't miss the nudity at all.
我们太过担忧与人关系密切
We're so worried about staying connected,
丝毫不顾我们立起来的心墙
ignoring the walls that are being erected.
我们被资讯给弄得晕头转向
We let the information confound us,
却忽略环绕在我们身边的爱
when there's so much love swirling around us,
而我们其实唯一需要做的是...
that all we need to do is --
网又好了
Wi-Fi's back on!
我怪我自己
I blame myself.
"学校成绩好吗 送你一顶帽子"
"You got an A? Have a hat."
"你膝盖擦破了吗 送你一顶帽子"
"You skinned your knee? Have a hat."
抱歉让你们久等了
Sorry for making you guys wait.
意外地花了比我预料的时间还久
It took me a little longer than I thought
才能回到曼尼这个身份
to find my way back to Manny.
太棒 太赞了
Bravo, bravo!
又一次大成功
Another triumph, eh?
谢谢
Thanks.
我真的觉得这次的作品不一般
You know, I really think I have something here.
我看与其坐游轮去玩
Maybe instead of going on that cruise,
我还是留在家里继续打磨这...
I should stay home and work on --
你必须得去
You are going on that cruise!
这对你很有好处啊
It's gonna be good for you.
你爸爸为这事也废了很多心思
it's so important for your father.
他都计划了一整个冒险呢
He planned a whole adventure!
我们会在洪都拉斯喝龙舌兰
We'll drink tequila in Honduras.
在巴厘岛与海豚共游
We'll swim with the dolphins in Bali.
但当我们到了巴拿马运河那里
But when we travel through the Panama Canal,
我们会需要做点简单的家政服务工作
we'll be required to do some light housekeeping.
这是定好的条件
It's part of the deal.
好吧
Okay, then.
我去拿一下我的东西
I'll just go grab my stuff
然后跟我的粉丝合影一下
and take some selfies with my fan.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria, dime --
为什么你突然对游轮旅改变态度了
why are you suddenly so on board with this trip?
他这一生被我保护成温室里的花朵
I've sheltered him for too long.
他需要有值得写出来的真实冒险
He needs something real that he can write about.
带他去最龙蛇混杂的酒吧
Take him to the seediest bars,
把他介绍给骗徒
introduce him to con men.
让他体会到危险
Let him taste danger.
但别让他吃虾 他一吃虾眼皮就会肿
But not shrimp, because it makes his eyelid feel funny.
先生 不许你戴
No, senor!
我绝不会让这个恶习传承下来
The cycle ends here!
你不是吧 你就这么卖我求荣吗
Really? You just sold me out for a job?
亲爱的 他想要个冒险家
Honey, he wants a risk-taker.
如果我毁了你们俩男孩的旅行 我多罪大恶极啊
How's it going to look if I squash your boys' trip?
什么男孩旅行 这可是离开地球
Boys' trip?! We're leaving the planet!
你知道过山车最可怕的是什么吗
You know the scariest part of a roller coaster?
是坐整整一个月的过山车
It's a month of that!
老爸 你不想去太空吗
Dad, you don't want to go to space?
我想去啊
No, I do.
我只是... 有点担心
I-I just -- I worry
这种等爸爸回家的经历会造成心理创伤...
that it might be too traumatic for you --
不会啊 会是很值得跟孩子们说的故事
Oh, no, it'll be fun to tell the kids
他们的外公是个宇航员
their Pop-Pop is an astronaut.
爆爆[外公]很可能会是我此生最后发出的声音
Pop-Pop might be the last sound I make.
克莱尔 如果不麻烦
Claire, if it's not too much trouble,
能请你帮我选好一张全家福照片吗
would you please, um, pick out a family photo for me to clutch
当我系绳断了 无止尽在太空翻转时可以拿着
after my tether snaps and I tumble endlessly through the void?
比较有可能的应该是
It is much more likely
当你重新进入大气层时 直接被烧成灰烬
that you will just incinerate upon re-entry.
你们在聊上太空的事吗
You guys talking about space?
是啊
Yeah.
听我说 兄弟
Um...look, buddy,
我很感谢这一切 但我不想去
I appreciate all this, but I don't want to go.
什么
What?
对不起 我真的很怕
I'm sorry. I'm just so scared.
但你是我的定海神针
But y-you're my rock.
我不... 没有你我做不到
I-I can't -- I can't do this without you.
我是你的定海神针吗
I'm your rock?
我给我们添了什么麻烦啊
What did I get us into?
我其实都不想去
I didn't even want to go.
我只是想在贝佐斯
I just wanted to look cool in front of Bezos
伊隆与扎扎面前耍酷罢了
and Elon and Zuck-Zuck.
你是为了这种原因才想去的吗
That's the reason why you're going?
恕我直言 把白男发射到太空中
I'm sorry, but launching white dudes into space
已经不酷很多年了
hasn't been cool for years.
但镜头在拍
But the cameras.
我怎么样才能安全下庄
How am I going to get out of this?
如果你只是想耍帅
Well, if you're trying to look cool,
你就举办一个华丽的活动
just throw some splashy event
把去太空的机会拍卖掉再捐给慈善机构就行
and auction off the space trip to charity.
感觉能行
That could work.
哪种慈善机构啊
What kind of charity?
最近跟狼有关的慈善机构挺火
Wolves are hot right now.
我喜欢
I love that.
我要拯救狼群
I'm going to save the wolves!
我们是要拯救 不是要灭狼 对吧
We're saving them, right? Yeah.
我喜欢你这样不走寻常路
I like the way you think outside the box.
我可能有个很不错的工作岗位可以给你
I may have a really interesting job opportunity for you.
海莉 我们说不定可以一起工作呢
Haley, we could be working together!
没 这是个一个人的职位
No, it's really just the one job.
菲尔 虽然不是太空之旅
And, Phil, while it's not a trip to space,
但我希望菲尔·邓菲狼群中心
I hope that the Phil Dunphy Center for Wolves
能够配得上你改变我人生的恩情
will be a fitting honor for the man who changed my life.
我们会举办一个盛大开幕仪式
We'll have a big opening ceremony.
你们可以看看所有的狼们
You'll meet all the wolves!
我们到镜头前再来演一次吧
Now let's go do this again in front of the cameras!
我很怕狼
I'm terrified of wolves!
太好了 你来了
Oh, good, you're here.
曼尼马上要给我展示他新的游轮装
Manny's about to model his new cruise wear for me.
看来有好戏看了
This should be good.
杰 别让他自我羞耻
Jay, don't make him self-conscious.
答应我你会管住自己的嘴
Promise you're going to be nice.
很聪明
Very smart.
谢谢夸张 老妈
Thanks, Mom.
杰 你觉得呢
Jay, what do you think?
袋鼠船长[形似]你好
Hey, El Capitan Kangaroo.
您哪位啊 是奇人异事先生[形似]吗
What are you, the Untalented Mr. Ripley?
你甚至应该去巴哈马群岛指挥交通
You should be directing traffic in the Bahamas.
歌手坦尼尔[船长打扮]打来了
Tennille called...
我吐槽过这个了没
D-Did I do that one yet?
总之 她觉得你看起来就像80年代电影里
Anyway, she thinks you look like the kid in an '80s movie
人见人憎的死小孩
we're supposed to hate.
你看起来很赞啊
You look amazing.
赞到像贵族家庭里
Amazing-ly like the last Kennedy picked
玩球时最后被人选进队的废柴
in a touch football game.
这些吐槽太赞了 我必须得去跟他说
These are too good. I gotta tell him.
曼尼 再把服装穿上
Manny, put the outfit back on!